Developer Ethan Ferrier

Cell: (503) 983-3730 Email: Fethanerrier@gmail.com Address: Redding, California

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-ferrier-891bb6155/

GitHub: https://github.com/F-Ethan

Personal Summary

A motivated and creative full stack developer with the technical skills to see any project through to the end. Specializes in light weight development through refinement and problem solving. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a full stack developer.

Languages / Frameworks

Ionic ***** Angular *** React *** Python *** Django *** Flask **

 Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, JavaScript (JS), Ionic, TypeScript (TS), Es6, React, Angular, AJAX, Node, Express, Mongo dB, Mongoose, Passport, WebAPI, Python, Django, Flask, Beautiful Soup

Technologies

 VisualStudio2015, Sublime Text 3, Git, MVC, NPM, Bower, Atom, Dependency Injection, Heroku, mLab

Other Skills

Agile Methodologies, SCRUM, Unit Testing

Projects

Web Tracker -https://github.com/F-Ethan/my_app

This is an online application for tracking maintenance history, rental location and rental dates for an equipment rental company. http://pursuit.pythonanywhere.com

- Built in python with Django
- MySql, Html, CSS, JavaScript

JavaScript APi -https://github.com/F-Ethan/JaveScript-API

This is a Api example in Javascript I worked though for school

• Html, CSS, JavaScript

Education

Bethel Tech Full Stack Web: December 2019 – August 2020

- Learned how to build web applications using Ionic, Angular, and react. Acquired skills to program using javascript, and to make a database with MySql. Built a backend with Express and spent 20 hours a week programming and building web applications.
- Bethel School of Technology, powered by WozU, Apple's co-founder Steve Wozniak's coding bootcamp
- universityhttps://www.newsweek.com/insights/the-top-coding-schoolsof-2019/bethel-school-technology

Harvard's CS50 Web Programing with Python and Javascript: January 2019 - May 2019

 Learned to Develop Web applications with python building with both Flask and Django and tying into MySql Databases. Spent 20 hours a week working on programing in Python

College Connections: September 2013 - May 2014

- Highschool diploma
- 30 college Credits

Stanford Summer Class: June 2013 - August 2013

• 12 college credits credits

Work History

Intern to the Operations Manager, Bethel school: September 2016 - May 2017

- Oversaw maintenance of Schools web application
- Reconciled 20 years of schools student records from two databases and all their paper records.
- Worked with developers to update schools web application

Computer Technician, Mikes Computer repair: June 2016 - August 2016

Virus removal

- Screen repair
- New computer setup

Front End Manager, Food Maxx: April 2014 - April 2017

- In charge of up to twenty employees at one time
- Count checkers tills and safe and make sure they balance
- Deal with all unsatisfied customers